A Guide to the Carl Van Vechten-Mark Lutz Collection,
Rare Books and Special Collections, Boatwright Library, University of Richmond
- Geometric-Patterned Box: Material by Carl Van Vechten.
  - The Yale University Library Gazette, Vol. 38, No. 2 1963 (Box 4:13)
    (October 1963). Piece by Carl Van Vechten, pp. 43-50, "Rogue Elephant in Porcelain," purporting to describe Wallace Stevens [poet]. Inscribed by Van Vechten: "For dearest Bino with love from Carlo. November 8, 1963. New York."
  - The Yale University Library Gazette, Vol. 22, No. 3 1947 (Box 4:14)
    (November 1947 [?]). pp. 85-92 contain a piece by Carl Van Vechten, "How I Remember Joseph Hergesheimer [writer]." A reproduced portrait of the man by Florine Stettheimer follows on p. 93.Inscribed by Van Vechten: "Dear Mark, for you with love, Carl Van Vechten. January 25, 1948."
  - Challenge: A Literary Quarterly, Vol. I, No. 2 1934 (Box 4:15)
    (September 1934). P. 23, a brief comment on"the Negro Renaissance" by Carl Van Vechten, entitled, appropriately enough, "Carl Van Vechten comments." Signed:"Carl Van Vechten. September 8, 1934. New York."
  - The American Record Guide, Vol. 26, No. 10 1960 (Box 4:16)
    (June 1960). pp. 778-781, article by Van Vechten:"Why Music is so Unpopular." Prior to these pages he wrote over his photograph opposite " Evviva Carlo,"by the Editor: "For dearest Bino on June 17, 1960 with love from Carlo, loving octogenarian."
  - Reprinted article by Carl Van Vechten: 1942 (Box 4:17)
    "The James Weldon Johnson Collection at Yale." Appeared in Crisis, July 1942. Inscribed by Van Vechten: "For Mark with love from Carl Van Vechten. July 29, 1942. New York."
  - Reprint of Carl Van Vechten's article: 1940 (Box 4:18)
    "The Proposed J. W. Johnson Memorial," in Opportunity: The Journal of Negro Life, February, 1940.
- "Carl Van Vechten Pamphlets"
  - Photograph of bronze bust of Carl Van Vechten by Max Ewing(?) No Date (Box 5:1a)
  - Lithograph of Portrait of Carl Van Vechten by Robert V. Cherlie[?] No Date (Box 5:1b)
  - "Five Old English Ditties with Music by Carl Van Vechten." June 24, 1933 (Box 5:2)
    Explanatory note and dedicatory line by Van Vechten.
  - Acid-decayed folder with hand-written title: "Van Vechten's List of his Books presented to The New York Public Library." Above is a signed explanatory piece addressed to his close friend, Mark Lutz,"... New York, June 24, 1941." June 24, 1941 (Box 5:3)
  - Stan' Still Jordan, the music of a Negro Spiritual, arranged by J. Rosamond Johnson--1926, by Harold Flammer, Inc., New York. 1926 (Box 5:4)
    On the title page: "To my esteemed friend, Carl Van Vechten, with Sincere Admiration, J. Rosamond."
  - The Music of Nigger Heaven Blues, presented by the Manhatters. 1927 (Box 5:5)
    Words by George S. Oppenheimer; music by Alfred Nathan, Jr. Copyright 1927 by De Sylva, Brown & Henderson, Inc., New York.
  - Four-paged typescript entitled, "American Negro Exhibition," at Syracuse University Library, December, 1945" 1945 (Box 5:6)
    A note by Carl Van Vechten on the exhibit containing his photographs is signed: "Carl Van Vechten, December, 1945
  - Two-page typescript, "News from the American Academy of Arts & Letters." Deals with "Rare Van Vechten Portrait-Photograph on view." September 12,1967 (Box 5:7)
  - Replica of a Tribute in The New York Public Library Bulletin, June 15, 1960. 1960 (Box 5:8)
    Inscribed to: "Carl Van Vechten Who, over a period of almost two decades, has been a Benefactor of... on the occasion of your eightieth birthday... ." Beneath in Van Vechten's hand:"For dear Marco, with love from Carlo. August 17, 1960."
  - The issue of the N. Y. P. L. Bulletin cited above. June 15, 1960 (Box 5:9)
  - Fiske University, Nashville, Tennessee; 81st. Annual May 28-31, 1955 (Box 5:10)
    Commencement, May 28-30, 1955. Honorary degree of Doctor of Literature conferred upon Carl Van Vechten. Contains newspaper clipping with photograph of presentation taken from The Nashville Tennessean, May 31, 1955.
  - Unique picture of a cat grooming itself on the front of a box June 24, 1933 (Box 5:11)
    Holding Edition No. 1 of The Tiger in the House, by Carl Van Vechten. Green paper. New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1933. The author has written on this: "This was pictured on the original box which held the edition No. 1 of the Tiger. A Philadelphia bookseller objected to the cat's occupation and a more demure label was pasted on. Mark from Carl. June 24, 1933."
  - Yale University Exercises marking the Opening of the James Weldon Johnson Memorial Collection of Negro Arts & Letters, founded by Carl Van Vechten. Sprague Memorial Hall, January 7, 1950. January 7, 1950 (Box 5:12)
    Page 4 has a reduced sized replica of the Resolution of Gratitude to Carl Van Vechten. December 10, 1949.
  - Carl Van Vechten (a facsimile of his signature rendered in green.) February 18, 1977 (Box 5:13)
    Published by the Goodwill Gallery in conjunction with an exhibition of forty (40) photographs by Carl Van Vechten. First publication, No. 18, 1977. Estate of Carl Van Vechten.
  - "Harold'sMother suffers stroke of paralysis. Posed Expressly for The Chicago American, with Miss Elsie Buerlier of the 'Royal Chef' Company as Mrs. Borradale." circa 1905 (Box 5:14a)
    Above this is inscribed by Van Vechten: "Note: One of the illustrations for a novel which ran serially in The Chicago American, circa 1905. I posed for the hero! C. V. V." Newspaper clipping pasted on cardboard.
  - Another clipping taken from the above without comment. circa 1905 (Box 5:14b)
  - Color reproduction of a satiristic portrayal of Carl Van Vechten by Miguel Corrubias. (Box 5:15)
    Inscribed by Van Vechten beneath in appropriate green ink are the words:"For Marco from Carlo. New York, August 8, 1939."
  - Two-page typescript--(work of an amateur journalist, Carl Van Vechten?)--addressed to: *"My dear uncle and Aunt," being a graphic description of a disastrous fire in a Chicago theatre on January 5, 1903. Carl Van Vechten January 5-1903 312 East Eeins[?] St. Chicago." 1-5-1903 (Box 5:16)
- Miscellaneous Carl Van Vechten Materials
  - Two Letters from Willa Cather to Carl Van Vechten. 1937 (Box 6:1)
    One of the above incorrectly dated "1927." Also included in this folder are photocopies of the letters, plus analysis by G. E. Van Wissink.
  - Various pamphlets, programmes, and so forth to which Carl Van Vechten contributed in some way. 1925-1947 (Box 6:2)
    Most of these bear his signature with a brief commentary.
  - Booklets, broadsheets, and typescripts by, for, or of Carl Van Vechten. 1933-1964 (Box 6:3)
  - Saturday Review containing Van Vechten reviews 1953-1956 (Box 6:4)
  - The Publishers' Weekly, Vol. 105, No. 7. 2-16-1924 (Box 6:5)
    Van Vechten Bibliography.
  - The Theatre Annual, pp. 32-38 by Carl Van Vechten. 1943 (Box 6:6)
  - New Mexico Quarterly (Summer 1951). (Box 6:7)
  - Carl Van Vechten mentioned twice. Taos period--Mabel Dodge Luhan, Spud Johnson, and others. (Box 6:8)
  - Letter to Fania Marinoff [Van Vechten's wife] dated May 24, 1938, from Paul Leyersac [?] of 151 East 51st Street, New York. He sends a copy of Oh It's perfectly Fine --together with his apologies for not having done so sooner. He extends "Kindest regards' to "Mr. Van Vechten." 5-24-1938 (Box 6:8)
  - A List of those who signed their names in, and in some cases contributed to, a commemorative tribute in book form: Alfred A. Knopf: Quarter Century, 1915-1940. Carl Van Vechten's contribution was a photographic portrait of Knopf on an opening page. 1940 (Box 6:9)
  - Typewritten Cast of a Play--with Carl Van Vechten and Fania Marinoff heading it. No Date (Box 6:10)
  - Scrap of a Booklist, *signed by Willa Cather March 1932 (Box 6:*11)
  - Newspaper clippings, Carl Van Vechten, various. Various (Box 6:12)
- Mark Lutz Materials
  - Magazines containing articles by Earle Lutz (Box 7:1)
  - Autograph Collectors' Journal, Vol. V, No. 3 (Spring 1953), pp. 32-36. 1953 (Box 7:1a)
    Article entitled, "Soldier Newspapers in the Civil War."
  - Two copies of the Bulletin of the New York Public Library, Vol. 57, No. 9 (September 1953), pp. 461-463. 1953 (Box 7:1b)
    Article entitled, "'Stars and Stripes' Now a Symbol."
  - Two copies of the Journal of the Illinois State Historical Society, Vol. XLVI, No. 2 (Summer 1953), pp. 132-141. 1953 (Box 7:1c)
    Article entitled, "The Stars and Stripes of the Illinois Boys in Blue."
  - Signed dedicatory copy of With Formality and Elegance: A Selection of Inscriptions to Bruce Kellner from Carl Van Vechten. *"Bruce Kellner, 26 November, 1968." 1968 (Box 7:*2)
  - Twice inscribed copy of The Reviewer [Richmond, VA] Vol. IV, No. 1 (January, 1924). 1924 (Box 7:**3)
    pp. 98-103 contain Carl Van Vechten's "Pastiches et Pistaches." The first "Pastiche" is "The Sabbath Glee Club of Richmond"--a Negro weekly social event. The Reviewer was founded in 1921 by Richmonders Emily Clark and Hunter Stagg. It ceased publication in the summer of 1924. Both Lutz and Van Vechten had social contacts with these editors. Gertrude Stein also had a piece in this literary magazine entitled, "An Indian Boy." The front cover bears the List of Contents and beside her entry she wrote: *"Mark Earl[?] Each[?] What [?] and [?] It happens To be true Gtde St." Van Vechten's response: *"Dear M L In [?] Queensborough [Richmond] These notes written For (and also [?] about) Queensborough! Will be [?] To M L!" Penned in green ink top left-hand corner of title page of " Pastiches et Pistaches."
  - Inscribed article by Carl Van Vechten in Ellen Glasgow, 1928 by Dorothea Lawrance Mann. Garden City, New York: Doubleday, Page & Company, 1927, pp. 39-42. (Box 7:*4)
    'A Virginia Lady dissects a Virginia Gentleman.' *"Dear Mark, From Carl, these lines on a book about Queensborough [Richmond, VA]. June 27, 192[8?] New York."
  - Why and What, an advertising vehicle for a magazine Called The Trend, of which Carl Van Vechten became Editor in 1917 [?]. 6-24-1933 (Box 7:*5)
    Flyleaf inscription reads: *"In 1917[?], returned from the wars--see Sacred and Profane Memories --I became editor of a magazine called The Trend and wrote this piece to advertise it.--Mark from Carl, 1933--June 24 New York."
  - Christmas Card from Earle & Elizabeth Lutz: About Fort Meade, Maryland -a booklet authored by Major Francis Lutz. No Date (Box 7:6a)
  - Another copy of above book. Transferred to Lutz Military Folder-Box IX: Folder 30. (Box 7:6b)
  - The Green Bulletin; New York unit of The Herb Society of America, Nos. 13 & 14 1953-1954. 1953-1954 (Box 7:7)
  - Cutting with photograph captioned: "Earle Lutz: Fighting Man." University of Richmond Alumni Bulletin, (Winter 1959) p. 12. 1959 (Box 7:8a)
  - Also a cut-out cardboard-backed photograph of Earl Lutz. No Date (Box 7:8b)
  - Three copies of Academy News, published by The Richmond Academy of Arts, Vol. I, No. 1 (January 1933)-Marl Lutz, Associate Editor. January, 1933 (Box 7:9)
  - Academy News, Vol. I, No. 1 (October, 1932) October, 1932 (Box 7:9a)
  - Academy News, Vol. I, No. 1 January, 1933 January, 1933 (Box 7:9b)
  - Academy News, Vol. I, No. 1 January, 1933 January, 1933 (Box 7:9b)
  - Philco News, January-December 1950 (Bound) *Mark Lutz, Associate Editor of this Philco Corporation's Department of Public Relations Publication. 1947 (Box 7:10)
  - Philco News, December 1950 (Christmas issue) December, 1950 (Box 7:11)
    *Mark Lutz, Editor of this Philco Corporation's Department of Public Relations publication.
  - The Choate Literary Magazine Supplement, Vol. IX, No. 2 (February 1935). February, 1935 (Box 7:12)
  - Germantowne Crier (Philadelphia) Vol. 20, No. 3 (September, 1968. Published by The Germantown Historical Association. Addressed to Mark Lutz, who was, at the time a resident of Germanstown. September 1968 (Box 7:13)
  - University of Richmond Alumni Bulletin, Vol. V, No. 2 (March 1941). * Mark Lutz has two pieces in this publication. (1) The leading article: "Warren Chappell, '26: Distinguished American Artist," pp. 1 & 20. (2) "From the Alumni Chapters" section; roughly one column under "Philadelphia." March 1941 (Box 7:14)
  - The Shield & Diamond of Pi Kappa Alpha, Vol. 79, No. 1 (September 1968), centennial issue. September 1968 (Box 7:15)
  - Byline --Philadelphia industrial Editors Association-Vol. V, No. 8 (April 1951). *Mark Lutz pictured on page 1. April 1951 (Box 7:16)
  - Stet: The House Magazine for House Editors, No. 211 (April 1958). On back page (p. 8), *Mark Lutz-1st Prize Winner, and picture. April 1958 (Box 7:17)
  - The Music Box Playbill (Sam H. Harris & *Irving Berlin, Managers) for a production of John Steinbeck's Of Mice and Men [c.1937] (1st. dramatization?). The opening night was Monday, December 13, 1937. Photographs of leading members of the cast are featured. December 13, 1937 (Box 7:18)
  - Program for the Richmond News LeaderJanuary 25, 1927 (Box 7:19)
    Presents Elizabeth Rothberg, Soprano (Prima Donna of The Metropolitan Opera Company In Recital; Max Jaffa on the piano." At the City Auditorium on January 25, 1927-com-mencing at 8.30 p.m.. Program notes by Mrs. Channing Ward.
  - Kristians Tonny [Dutch artist, 1907-19??-pupil of Pascin]. Gallery guide to an exhibition of his works. Galerie Th. Briant, Rue de Berri (Pres. le Faubourg St. Honor=eacute;,) Paris. Par Fevrier 2-15, 1927.February 2-15, 1927 (Box 7:20)
  - Scottsboro Limited: Four Poems and a Play in Verse. 1932 (Box 7:21)
    By Langston Hughes. Illustrated with Lithographs by Prentiss Taylor. New York: Golden Stair Press. Publishers advertisement, 1932. *Mark Lutz obtained a copy.
  - Men's Personnel Rules, Philadelphia Stage Door Canteen, American Theatre Wing. *Chairman of Men's Personnel Committee-Mark Lutz. No Date (Box 7:22)
  - The Saint Barbara Photographs. No Date (Box 7:23)
    57 archival photographic likenesses of various statues, framed paintings, murals, and stained glass images of this saint-[the patron saint of artillerymen] -housed in cathedrals, churches, chapels, and shrines throughout the Iberian peninsula. A typed accompanying inventory account for 31 only -of these a mere 28 have been cross-checked against the list.
  - Sts. Christopher and Sebastian. No Date (Box 7:24)
    Assorted materials-including two rather decayed typescripts for a potential play based on the former holy man and his life. Also a woodcut of an article about St. Christopher.
  - Two similar but not identical programs. Lucienne Boyer in Continental Varieties, New York. No Date (Box 7:25a & 25b)
  - French Casino Theatre Restaurant program-"French Casino Folies." No Date (Box 7:26)
  - The Imprint. No Date (Box 7:27)
    A booklet about woodcuts, lithographs, etc..
- Mark Lutz
  - The Connoisseur, American Edition (May 1961). May 1961 (Box 8:1)
    On p. 204, Under "Books Received" is an entry, Parker Lesley, Handbook of the Lillian Thomas Pratt Collection of Russian Imperial Jewels. Richmond, Virginia: Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1961.
  - Bundle of Thirteen (13) Souvenir programs of Colonel Basil's Opera et Ballet de Russe-*the earliest of these is an extremely lavish one for the Season 1914 at the Royal Theatre, Drury Lane, London. 1914-W. de (Box 8:2)
  - Horizon: A Review of Literature and Art. February 1948 (Box 8:3)
    Edited by Cyril Connolly. Vol. XVII, No. 9 (February 1948). Featuring The Loved One by Evelyn Waugh, making its prior-proper publication debut
  - Ben Hur. 1926. 1926 (Box 8:4)
    A Publication covering the history of the story, the making of the movie, and showing many stills from the film.
  - Brown-covered Notebook. No Date (Box 8:5)
    First page has notes for a book review of Joseph Hergesheimer latest. On the last page notes about St. Christopher-a passion with Lutz, along with St. Barbara. All the material in between seems to be about The Peep Show; its origin, history and mechanics.
  - Foreign language notebook. No Date (Box 8:6)
    Spanish. Probably for the research below-item No. 16.
- Mark Lutz Materials
  - Three Cards from an Admirer No Date (Box 9:1)
    (Seemingly an Actress)
  - Three Letters from James Branch Cabell to Mark Lutz: 1928, 1929, 1933 (Box 9:*2)
    3-31-1928 declines an invitation; 10-23-1929 2nd expresses appreciation; and 3-28-1933 also expresses appreciation.
  - Ellen Glasgow. 1941 (Box 9:*3)
    Letter, 4-14-1941. Short letter on high quality writing paper and maching envelope.
  - W. C. Handy. Two page letter to Mark Lutz. 1941 (Box 9:4)
    Typed and signed by his secretary.
  - Langston Hughes. Book parcel cover-hand addressed. 1930s (Box 9:5)
  - Langston Hughes. Letter to Mark Lutz. 1936 (Box 9:*6)
    Brief note (typed) agreeing to Sign books. "Best wishes" extended to Hunter Stagg (Richmond literary figure, and former co-editor-with Emily Clark-of the, by then defunct, Review.
  - Two letters recommending Mark Lutz for a Commission in the United States Naval Reserve Force. 1942 (Box 9:7)
    Both are dated September (22 & 23) 1942. One is from a Lieutenant Bryan, U.S.N.R., Office of Naval Procurement, Richmond, Virginia. The other is from the President of the Charles Bond Company, Philadelphia, PA-none other than Charles Bond.
  - Miss Ettie Stettheimer-Mark Lutz's letters to. 4-9-1936, 5-27-1936, 6-8-1936, 6-17-1936, 9-28-1936, 10-8-1936, 10-21-1936, 8-30-1949, 3-19-1951, *4-10-1951 (Box 9:8)
    The correspondence spans the years April 1936 up to April 1951. No Stettheimer letters survive in this collection, although one can safely assume they were written. Seven out of the ten in this folder were mailed in the mid 1930s, one in the late 1940s, and two in the late 1950s. The large gap between the last mid '30s letter and the first late '40s one is an unusually long period of time for a correspondence of this nature to lapse. It may well be that some of Mark Lutz's letters to Miss Stettheimer for this intervening blank were lost, or they may have been retained by the Stettheimer estate. A lot of the Lutz letters take the form of flattery and/or invitations of one sort or another. *In the last of these letters (4-10-1951) Mark Lutz divulges that, owing to moving house, he has given a sizeable roportion of his extensive and valuable library to the University of Pennsylvania.
  - Postcard-photographs of Three Modern Art Sculptures featuring "Muriel," by Max Ewing. 1930 (Box 9:9)
  - Later Bookplates & Marks of Rockwell Kent. 1937 (Box 9:10)
    Publishers' (Pynson Printers) advertising pamphlet, 1937. Also a clipping from a magazine regarding the same. The volume itself is housed in the Rare Book Room-Call No, Z996.K37 1937.
  - American War Mothers Membership Application Form 1932 (Box 9:11)
    Gives details of First Lieutenant Francis Earle Lutz, father of Mark Lutz, Headquarters Company, 110th Infantry Regiment, U.S. Army, together with his War Service on the Western Front. Dated September 15, 1932.
  - Several typesheets of information about the Confederate States of America's Naval School Ship, the Patrick Henry. Lists of Officers 1861-1863, and 1863-1865. No Date (Box 9:12)
  - Picture-postcard of a Venetian Room 1945 (Box 9:13)
    circa 1718, the Metropolitan Museum of Art. "To Mark Lutz" from "J. W. P." Mailed in New York City, July 12, 1945.
  - Three Picture-postcards: A Rodin Bronze Male Nude; "Cows Grazing," by Chabot; and the Cunard Liner BerengariaNo Date (Box 9:14)
  - From Random House a letter from Bennett A. Cerf (see note number 2 at the end of the guide) 1934 (Box 9:15)
    Comments on Mark Lutz's review of Gertrude Stein's Portraits and Prayers which appeared in the November 15, 1934, issue of the Richmond News Leader.
  - Clipping from the New Yorker1967 (Box 9:16)
    Following the death of Langston Hughes the New Yorker (December 30, 1967) carried a piece in its "Talk of the Town" section entitled: "Hughes at Columbia." The clipping preserves four columns-but not the complete article.
  - Odd bits of correspondence to Mark Lutz. Various (Box 9:17)
  - "Your Philadelphia Museum." Circa 1938(?) (Box 9:18)
    Typescript. Presumably Mark Lutz's handiwork.
  - Typescript notes for Review of "Ouida's" In a Winter City. New York: Boni & Live-right, 1928. 1928 (Box 9:19)
  - Fragment of typescript of Book Review of Hemingway's latest novel To Have and to Have Not [Harry Morgan; Key West; & Cuba] 1937 (Box 9:20)
    His only novel to be set in North America. Published 1937. [Scribners' Sons?]
  - Publishers' flyer for Andr=eacute; Levinson's Serge Lifar: Destin d'un Danseur. Paris: Editions Bernard Grasset, 1933? 1933 (Box 9:21)
  - Four Items 1942 (Box 9:22)
    : (1) Photograph-clipping from Life Magazine (September 20th. 1942)-of Sir Max Beerbohm; part of an article on Cambridge where he was the year's Rede Lecturer and spoke on Lytton Strachey, lamenting the "Century of the Common Man." (2) Postcard communication to Mark Lutz from New York Public Library. Date difficult to determine. (3) Subject/Page No. notes on both sides of a scrap of paper. No Date (4) Typed fragment: "Colossus is a very artful book." No Date
  - Incomplete draft of letter to James Weldon Johnson from Mark Lutz about the former's autobiography. Dated June 8, 1934. 1934 (Box 9:23)
  - "Bibliography of Gertrude Stein," 1935? (Box 9:24)
    Carbon-copy typescript. Latest publication date given is 1934 so the following year for these sheets would seem a reasonable assumption.
  - Seven sheets of carbon-copy typescript Designated "Gertrude Stein Reviews." circa 1934, 1933, 1934 (Box 9:25)
  - Publishers' advertising pamphlet for Painted Veils, a hard core pornographical work by one James Gibbons Huneker. New York: Boni & Liveright, 1920. 1920 (Box 9:26)
    Louis Bromfield's review of The Autobiography of Alice B. Toklas appeared in the New York Herald Tribune, September 3, 1933. Four Saints in Three Acts reviews came out in 1934. The Making of Americans was first reviewed in 1920. Clifton Fadiman reviewed it for the New Yorker, February 10, 1934.
  - Fragment of typescript No Date (Box 9:27)
    Typescript which would appear to relate to a series of interviews with a writer formerly a reporter with The Chicago American. Carl Van Vechten?-He started his career with it.
  - Two Letters from Alice Toklas 1934-35 (Box 9:28)
    , Written from the Hotel Algonquin, 59-65 West Forty-Fourth Street, New York, to Mark Lutz, 1123 West Franklin St. Richmond, Virginia. The first post-marked November 1, 1934; the second January 30, 1935.
  - Book reviews by Mark Lutz (Box 9:29)
    Folder of reviews. Photocopies made from decaying newsprint clippings.
  - Photocopies fragments taken from newspapers dealing with the military Lutz's career. (Box 9:30)
- Gertrude Stein Materials
  - Various (Box 10:1)
    Large Buff-colored Envelope containing photocopies of newspaper clippings apper-taining to Gertrude Stein.
  - "Gertrude Stein on Record." Two Record Companies' (Dorian Records and Folkways) advertising sheets/pamphlets. 1952 (Box 10:2)
  - Vogue (July 1, 1942). pp. 60, 61, & 70, article, "Gertrude Stein in France," by Th=eacute;r賥 Bonney. Five Photographs. 1942 (Box 10:3)
  - The Sketch, Vol. CLXXVIII, No. 2310 (May 5, 1937 ) 1937 (Box 10:4)
    Pictures and captions of "The Wedding Bouquet," Sadlers Wells Ballet arranged by Lord Berners; words by Gertrude Stein.
  - The University of Virginia Magazine, Vol. XCIII, No. 3 (January, 1935). 1935 (Box 10:5)
    pp. 2-4: "A Valentine for Gertrude Stein," by Dewitt Eldridge, in anticipation of her planned visit to the University of Virginia.
  - Two page typescript guide to an exhibition "Looking at Pictures with Gertrude Stein." No Date (Box 10:6)
  - The Reporter, Vol. 13, No. 2 (August 11, 1955). pp. 46-51, "Gertrude Stein's American Years," by Elizabeth Sprigge. 1955 (Box 10:7)
  - Two consecutive issues of Real America: The Out-spoken Magazine, Vol. 6, Nos. 4 & 5 (January, February, 1936). 1936 (Box 10:8)